What happens when you sleep?
Paranormal Activity is a horror, mystery film directed by Oren Peli.
After a young, middle-class couple moves into what seems like a typical suburban house, they become increasingly disturbed
by a presence that may or may not be demonic but is certainly the most active in the middle of the night.
Katie Featherston, played by Katie Featherston.
Micah Sloat, played by Micah Sloat.
The Psychic, played by Mark Fredrichs.
Amber, played by Amber Armstrong.
Diane, played by Ashley Palmer.
Exorcism Nanny (uncredited), played by Crystal Cartwright.
Paranormal Activity is a 2007 American found-footage supernatural horror film
produced, written, directed, photographed, and edited by Oren Peli.
It centers on a young couple (Katie Featherston and Micah Sloat) who are
haunted by a supernatural presence inside their home.
They then set up a camera to document what is haunting them.
The film uses found-footage conventions that were
mirrored in the later films of the series.
Originally developed by Peli as an independent feature and given film
festival screenings in 2007, the film was shot for $15,000.
It was then acquired by DreamWorks Pictures, then a Paramount Pictures subsidiary, who
modified the film, particularly with a new ending that cost an additional $200,000.
It was given a limited U.S.
release on September 25, 2009, and then a
nationwide release on October 16, 2009.
The film earned nearly $108 million at the U.S.
box office and a further $85 million internationally
for a worldwide total of $194 million.
Paramount would then solely acquire the U.S.
rights for $350,000.
It is often cited as the most profitable film ever made, based on proportionate return on investment, although
such figures are difficult to verify independently as this is likely to exclude marketing costs.
The film is the first installment in the Paranormal Activity film series.
A prequel, Paranormal Activity 2, was released in 2010.
The film explores themes of supernatural, haunting,
psychic, entity, demonic possession.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.